A Guide to the Papers of William Faulkner, 1929-1965
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of William Faulkner, 1929-1965
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7914
This collection consists of 35 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Mr. Massey on January 23, 1966.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains manuscripts and correspondence of William Faulkner.
Contents List
- Manuscripts
  - Untitled manuscript [Painter?- Forget? Christ.. ."] n.d., AMs, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - "Night Bird" n.d., TMs, 4 p. on 4 l.
  - Roscoe B. Fleming's "William Faulkner, A Major American Novelist" n.d., TMs, 10 p. on 10 l.
- Correspondence
  - William Faulkner to Ben Wasson 1933 Feb 12, TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - [George?] Lorimer to Morton Goldman 1934 Oct 1, TLS, 3 p. on 3 l.
  - William Faulkner to Morton Goldman 1935 Jan 23, TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bennett A. Cerf to Morton Goldman 1937 Jan 7, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bennett A. Cerf to Morton Goldman 1937 Jan 14, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Robert A. Haas to Morton Goldman 1938 Feb 15, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - William Faulkner to Morton Goldman 1938 Feb 28, TL, w/ env., 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Whit Burnett to [Morton] Goldman July 17, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - E[stelle] Faulkner to [Morton] Goldman n.d., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - William Faulkner to Mortona Goldman n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "Enclosed is the best short story in the year 1935.. ."
  - William Faulkner to Morton Goldman n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "Excuse not writing.. ." regarding "Drusilla"
  - William Faulkner to Morton Goldman n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "Writing Hal at once.. ."
  - William Faulkner to Morton Goldman n.d., TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
    The CHRISTMAS TREE story which you mention.. ."
  - [William Faulkner] to [Morton Goldman] n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "Good God yes, let them have.. ."
  - William Faulkner to Morton Goldman n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "Much obliged for getting offer.. ."
  - William Faulkner to Ben Wasson n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "What status on my balance.. ."
  - William Faulkner to Ben Wasson n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "I am going to get loose from Joyce.. ."
  - William Faulkner to Ben Wasson n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l., w/ autograph additions
    "My contract with M.G. M... ."
  - William Faulkner to Ben Wasson n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "I have Hayward's contract.. ."
  - William Faulkner to Ben Wasson n.d., TL, 2 p. on 2 l.
    "When I wrote Abernathy.. ."
  - William Faulkner to Ben Wasson n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "Here is another story.. ."
  - William Faulkner n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "The contract for 'Light in August'.. ."
  - William Faulkner to Ben Wasson n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "I have not finished typing yet.. ."
  - William Faulkner to [Ben Wasson] n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "I am sorry about crossing you up.. ."
  - William Faulkner to Ben Wasson n.d., TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "It's fine about the good price.. ."
  - William Faulkner to unknown n.d., AN fragment, 1 p. on 1 l.
    "Mrs. Marshall.. ."
- Documents
  - Agreement [agent's copy] for publication of The Sound and the Fury1929 Feb 18, D, 4 p. on 1 l.
  - Memorandum of agreement [agent's copy] for publication of A Novel1929 May, D, 4 p. on 1 l.
  - Memorandum of agreement [agent's copy] for publication of As I Lay Dying1931 Apr 3, D, 4 p. on 1 l.
  - Memorandum of agreement [agent's copy] for publication of short stories 1931 May 14, D, 4 p. on 1 l.
  - Charles Scribner's Sons Release to William Faulkner of copyright to "Spotted Horses" 1936 Sep 3, TDS, 1 p. on 1 l.
- Miscellaneous
  - William Faulkner to Morton Goldman [1934?], Envelope
  - Joseph Blotner's holograph listing of contents of Massy-Faulkner #7914 1965 May 7, Listing, 2 p. on 1 l.